<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&#39;m Abhijit Pai.</title>
    <link>https://abhijitpai000.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hi, I&#39;m Abhijit Pai.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abhijitpai000.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Moviebot Mike</title>
      <link>https://abhijitpai000.github.io/posts/moviebot-mike/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijitpai000.github.io/posts/moviebot-mike/</guid>
      <description>Features Mike predicts 9 user intents, makes recommendations for about 200 IMDb 7+ rated Bollywood movies from the 2010 - 2019 era based on plot similarity, gives movie plots, and drops movie dialogues in the conversation.
Related Links  Web app link (Heroku) Web app repo (Github) Model Training repo (Github)  NOTE: The web app is deployed on a free server which goes into sleep mode and takes about 10s for boot up, once loaded the bot will work as expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Product RecSys</title>
      <link>https://abhijitpai000.github.io/posts/product-recsys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijitpai000.github.io/posts/product-recsys/</guid>
      <description>About Using the customer orders and rating data from Olist E-Commerce Public Dataset, which has information about 100k orders made at multiple marketplaces in Brazil from 2016 to 2018, I trained 3 models that generate product recommendations.
NOTE - The granularity of orders in the dataset is at the product category level, thus recommendations are product categories in the true sense.
Related Links  Web app link (Heroku). Web app (Github) Model Training (Github)  NOTE: The web app is deployed on a free server which goes into sleep mode and takes about 10s for boot up, once loaded the bot will work as expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Grader</title>
      <link>https://abhijitpai000.github.io/posts/text-grader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijitpai000.github.io/posts/text-grader/</guid>
      <description>About Text Grader determines the readability of a given text using Flesch-Kincaid readability tests and provides stats about the text.
Related Links  Web app link (Heroku). Code (Github)  NOTE: The web app is deployed on a free server which goes into sleep mode and takes about 10s for boot up, once loaded the bot will work as expected.
How it Works When user inputs a text, backend performs to following.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Lifetime Value</title>
      <link>https://abhijitpai000.github.io/posts/customer-lifetime-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijitpai000.github.io/posts/customer-lifetime-value/</guid>
      <description>Overview Trained a Beta Geometric-Negative Binomial Distribution (BG/NBD) model that explains how frequently customers make purchases while they are still &amp;ldquo;alive&amp;rdquo; and how likely a customer is to churn in any given time period, using customer transactions of E-Commerce store Olist public dataset
Model Outcome
Trained Model Predicts Number of Purchases with an RMSE of 0.144 and is able to predict 99% of purchases in the test set.
Model vs Actual - Cumulative Transactions and Daily Transactions About Olist Dataset The dataset has information of 100k orders from 2016 to 2018 made at multiple marketplaces in Brazil, the orders are divided into 9 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictive Lead Scoring</title>
      <link>https://abhijitpai000.github.io/posts/predictive-lead-scoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijitpai000.github.io/posts/predictive-lead-scoring/</guid>
      <description>Overview Predictive Lead Scoring is a method used to analyze lead behavior in historical customer data to find patterns resulting in a positive business outcome, such as a closed deal with a client. In this study, I developed a lead scoring model using the Bank Marketing dataset, which contains the outcome of clients subscribing to a term deposit or not based on a direct marketing campaign performed by a Portuguese bank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Segmentation - RFM</title>
      <link>https://abhijitpai000.github.io/posts/customer-segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijitpai000.github.io/posts/customer-segmentation/</guid>
      <description>Overview Recency-Frequency-Monetary Value (RFM) is a quantitative technique used to analyze &amp;amp; group customers based on their purchase history by assigning numerical values (1 to K) for customer groups. In this study, I computed RFM for each customer based on their purchases (using definitions below), then applied the K-Means clustering algorithm, which aims to partition N-observations into K-clusters by assigning each observation a random cluster number (0 to K), based on nearest &amp;lsquo;Means&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retail Summer Sales</title>
      <link>https://abhijitpai000.github.io/posts/retail-summer-sales/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijitpai000.github.io/posts/retail-summer-sales/</guid>
      <description>Understanding how well a product that is published on the E-Commerce platform Wish is going to sell using Machine Learning.
Overview In this study, I extracted 10 significant features out of 43 provided in the dataset and trained a Linear Regression model that predicts &amp;ldquo;units_sold&amp;rdquo; of products.
Evaluation Metrics used: Mean absolute error and R-Squared
Findings It is observed that out of the 10 features, products marked rating 3 and 5 have a significant positive impact on sales, followed by merchants who used ad boosts, their total rating count, discount percent on the product, with a retail price of the product having a significant negative impact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://abhijitpai000.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijitpai000.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact Me input, textarea {display:block;padding:10px;border:solid 2px;box-shadow:0 0 15px 4px rgba(0,0,0,0.06);border-radius:10px;width: 40%;outline: none;}input:focus {box-shadow: 0 0 5px rgba(81, 203, 238, 1);border: 1px solid rgba(81, 203, 238, 1);}textarea:focus {box-shadow: 0 0 5px rgba(81, 203, 238, 1);border: 1px solid rgba(81, 203, 238, 1);}button {border-radius: 10px; border: solid 2px; padding: 5px; color: black; cursor: pointer;font-weight: bold;outline: none;margin-top:10px;}button:hover {background:#659dbd;color: white;}I&amp;rsquo;m currently looking for opportunities in the ML space, if you want to collaborate on a project feel free to contact me!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://abhijitpai000.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijitpai000.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I like Applied Machine Learning, enjoy the process of building ML-powered web apps.
Professionally, I have about 3 years of experience at Amazon, in the department of Alexa Data Services, part of the ML Ops team working on Alexa&amp;rsquo;s development.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently looking for opportunities in the ML space!
Skills Primary    Domain  Frameworks/Libraries/Packages      Machine Learning Python, scikit-learn, scikit-surprise, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib &amp;amp; Seaborn.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
